Srinivasan Thathankudi Chakkarapani

Digital Product Designer (UI-UX)

www.srinivasan.design +1 312-973-6557

tcsreeni93@gmail.com

Summary

A passionate full spectrum product designer with years of experience in designing and shipping digital products for Food Tech, Fin Tech & SaaS companies. I'm an advocate for functional, aesthetic and user-centred products which has an impact on people's life solving a need. I have a strong notion that a good product is a concoction of design and technology.

Education

Master of Science, Human Computer Interaction

DePaul University, Chicago - June 2020 (Expected)

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering

SASTRA University, India - May 2015

Professional Experience

User Experience Design Intern, Google

June 2019 - September 2019

Designed and shipped the first version of design system for the Google Ad Manager platform by collaborating with senior interaction designers, developers and visual design lead.

Interaction Designer, Zeta

February 2018 - August 2018

Worked on two stealth mode products bundled inside the Zeta Optima product which focuses on digitising the tax benefits for employers & employees on web and mobile platforms. Initiated & framed a design system for products designed across the company.

Product Designer, Zoho Corporation

December 2015 - January 2018

Designed and shipped the Zoho Sheet product on mobile platforms as the primary product designer. I worked on designing the application for iOS and Android platforms from ideating features, wireframing to setting visual standards and framing a design system. Worked closely with the developers, product managers to effectively ship the product to the respective application stores which onboard many web application users to the mobile platforms.

Product Designer, Holachef

June 2015 - December 2015

Designed and shipped the second version of the iOS and Android Application for the company. Wore the hat of web designer in redesigning the primary web product. Designed mobile products for chefs and delivery executives which helped in the functioning of the business.

Key Skills

Information Architecture

Contextual Inquiry

Wireframing

Interaction Design

Visual Design

Prototyping

Motion Design

Usablity Testing

Design Systems

Mobile App Design

Web Design

Low/ High fidelity mockups

User Research

Tools

Wireframing

Balsamiq, Axure RP.

Design

Sketch, Adobe Photoshop Illustrator & XD, Figma.

Prototyping

Principle, Adobe After Effects, Framer X, Marvel, Invision.

Development

HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Activities

Student Member at the DePaul XD Roundtable